Doyle Turner

Lead, Full Stack Engineer w/ Technology Spanning Passion

Chattanooga TN United States http://doyleturner.net

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I work with incredible people, to create amazing tools, which do cool things. Some of the software has been around manufacturing, some in HR, but some of my favorites have been in healthcare. I've worked as a lone-ranger and as a team member. Although, even as the only engineer I had some pretty knowledgeable business folks to help develop requirements.

I prefer working on small-to-mid-sized teams, or solution groups within large environments. I like OOP and Functional Programming, having yet to hear anything that makes one more valuable than the other at every problem. I believe in the right tool for the right job. I write JavaScript, C#, Clojure, PHP, Java, and a bunch of languages friendly to these. I have a bias for agile facilitation over SDLC project management approaches because of proven results.

Good fortune has allowed me the ability and opportunity to lead. My curiosity means I'm not content to "just write code." I find meaningful solutions to problems affecting people. Some of those problems have been in making things fast and well. There have been solutions to issues with finding, training, and keeping people that I've helped solve through software. I've written some code that I hope and believe has improved medicine, both from a patient and payer/payee point-of-view.

Personal Mission Statement:

Grow continually; have a positive impact on the world, and keep family at the center of it all.

Goals:

- Continue strengthening my current skill-set, pick-up new skills through trial-error-guidance-and-observance, lose some bad habits that I don't even know I have yet, and learn to be.
- Participate in the development community through open-source contributions, taking out the trash at conferences, and maybe present some
 of the lessons I pick up along the way.
- Remain a driving force for interactive, agile development practices within the development teams and companies I'm associated.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer | Technical Lead | Meditract | Tractmanager | Chattanooga, TN | From May 2017 to present

C#, ASP.NET, MVC, Azure, JavaScript, TypeScript, SASS, Knockout, Angular, RhinoMocks, Jira, Confluence, TFS, VSTS, GIT, Clojure, AWS, OOP, Functional Programming, Hiccup, ReFrame, React

Initially brought in to lead one of five distributed development teams. Quickly identified, and mitigated gaps with over-architecture that didn't effectively allow evolving architecture needed for the project. Transitioned to technical lead of the project with responsibility including ensuring that path of the project fell in line with corporate goals and project requirements. As the Technical Lead, I became responsible for the technical implementation concerns for a high-profile, high-impact, multi-million dollar, greenfield development effort to bring the companies offerings into the future. I also remained "in the code" working to spend at least 30% of my time on the project as lead contributing to source directly in addition to mentoring more Jr. Engineers.

Close work with the Sr. Director of Project Development, Scrum Master, VP of Technology Delivery, and C-Suite on one side and a very talented Engineering Team of the other helped to bring the project on track and in line with the plans of both Meditract and the parent company Tractmanager. This role allowed me to work directly with members of the executive team and have a significant impact of decisions across the enterprise.

Key Contributions:

Lead the company shift from a diverse source control tool list to git as defacto across the enterprise.

Pushed for the adoption of evolving architecture during the development process.

Worked with business and other engineers to explore, draft, vet, and finalize decisions throughout the development process.

Continually aligned technology with emerging and known business requirements.

Worked directly to move the project and company from a tightly controlled and failing waterfall approach to an agile approach across project and business domains.

.Net Engineer Advanced | Zirmed | Louisville, KY | From Aug 2016 to May 2017

C#, ASP.NET, MVC, JavaScript, Node Js, MediatR, CQRS, GIT, TFS, WCF, DDD, OOP

Comprise part of a scrum team focused on greenfield development in the healthcare industry. The primary focus of the team is on Value-Based-Care efforts that represent the future of the healthcare industry.

Responsible for being an active member of the team supporting scrum efforts in an agile environment. The workflow included participation in backlog refinement, sprint planning, twice weekly stand-ups, and retrospectives for a three-week sprint cycle.

Responsible for integration of NodeJs for automation of builds through integration into VS Environment.

Application Developer | Mercer (TekSystems Contract) | Louisville, KY | From Dec 2015 to Jul 2016

- C#, ASP.NET, MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, Flux, Nodejs, SOA, WCF, Jenkins, Selenium
- · Modernization of legacy applications
- Development of new components, applications, and extensions

During my time at Mercer, I was a participating facilitator of an agile team that consisted of a combination off-shore, telecommute, and inoffice staff of BAs, Test Engineers, QA Engineers, and Software Engineers. We worked within a formalized scrum team.

Software Engineer | Farm Credit Mid-America (Click IT Contract) | Louisville, KY | From Jul 2015 to Nov 2015

- C#, ASP.NET, MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, Telerik Tools, Kendo UI, EF, AngularJs
- Modernization of legacy applications
- Development of new Web APIs, components, and applications w/ front ends built on a variety of platforms including Angular and Kendo UI.
- Incorporation of custom security token system into applications
- Work as part of a Scrum Team directly under a leader in agile thinking in the region. A highlight of this role was the direct exposure I received to philosophies that are core to agile practices. Working under a Certified Scrum Coach I gained insight into the how and why of agile engineering practices as applied to business.

Software Engineer | Link-Belt Construction Equipment (AeroTek Contract) | Lexington, KY | From Jan 2015 to Jun 2015

- · C#, ASP.NET, MVC, WPF, JavaScript, jQuery
- Development of internal applications (web and desktop)
- Independent addition of new features to existing partner portal
- Establishment of Crystal Reports for business analysis to accompany new applications and extensions
- Support of legacy applications as needed (AS400/DB2 DataFiles)

Software Engineer | Northern Contours | Corbin, KY | From Jun 2014 to Jan 2015

C#, ASP.NET, MVC, WPF, JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, Telerik DevCraft, Kendo

- Particiapated in development of a new website including the addition of photo cropping system appropriate for web and desktop use.
- Part of the team that advanced a cutting-edge intranet application used at several manufacturing plants throughout the world
- Replacement of antiquated reporting system that used Crystal Reports with an advanced solution leveraging Telerik Reports
- Extended a WPF solution to integrate the new Telerik Reports while continuing to use Crystal Reports until the full company transition could wrap up.
- Support and maintenance

Projects consisted of a shared C# backend, MVC, and Angular.Js for all front-end interaction on web components. WPF on Desktop implementations.

Software Engineer | Lexington-Fayette-Urban County Government (TekSystems contract) | Lexington, KY | From Feb 2014 to Jun 2014

C#, ASP.NET, VB.net, MVC, SQL, SSMS, T-SQL, Partially telecommute

- · Create a solution for managing permits in the city
- Initial research and design of an application for leveraging GIS data to analyze bicycle transportation and visualize with Google Maps API.
- Renovate existing applications and redeployed to new mediums where appropriate
- Full SDLC development (Spiral)
- · Legacy application support

IT Specialist/Generalist | Automotive Systems, Inc. | London, KY | From Apr 2012 to Feb 2014

- Analyze existing administration tools on PHP based intranet site and use various methods of development to implement changes that are required to improve functionality and implement new tools
- Provide new HTML5 & CSS3 front end for the intranet site
- Modernize intranet site with new icons, updated contextual code (HTML) and extraction of styling to new external CSS
- · Leverage available tools to create or modify design elements. Primary tools include Adobe Create Suite (Photoshop & Illustrator)
- · Use multiple methodologies to provide applications for supporting production & quality control
- Position included a heavy focus on new application development to meet the overall needs of the company while allowing users immediate adoption of solutions
- Projects included research and initial development of biometric security application with C# implementation and MS SQL backend
- Manage several Window Servers (2003, 2008, and 2012) including Active Directory, Print Server, WAMPSERVER and file management
- · Provided mechanism for backup of data and support to onsite staff

Much of the development was telecommute from home office, but role still required a large onsite component.

IT Consultant | Owner | Central KY Technology | Kentucky | From May 2008 to Jan 2016

- Design and development of web applications, APIs, tooling, utilities, and desktop applications.
- Planned and performed customization of third-party and open source software.
- · Project planning and staff augmentation.
- Custom software deployment, deployment, maintenance, and analysis.

EDUCATION

Kaplan University | http://www.kaplan.edu | From Apr 2010 to May

2012 Area of Study/Major: Information Technology

Completed Associate of Applied Science with Dual Focus in Web Design and Application Development Cum Laude (3.5 GPA).

Kaplan University | http://www.kaplan.edu | From Jul 2012 to Mar 2014

Area of Study/Major: Information Technology

B.S in Information Technology awarded Summa Cum Laude (3.56 CGPA).

Kaplan University | http://www.kaplan.edu | From Mar 2014 to Jan

2017 Area of Study/Major: Information Technology

Completed MSIT with a focus in Information Security and Assurance along with matching Graduate Certificate

Kaplan University | http://www.kaplan.edu | From Nov 2016 to Jan 2017

Area of Study/Major: Information Security

Graduate Certificate in Information Security

•